

# **Personal Info**

#### Name

Fábio Miguel Alves Ferreira

## **Phone Number**

927671290

## Location

Santarém, Portugal

#### **Email**

me@fabiof.dev

## LinkedIn

https://linkedin.com/in/fabio-m-ferreira

#### **GitHub**

https://github.com/fabio-m-ferreira

## **Portfolio**

https://fabiof.dev

# **Soft Skills**

- Communication
- Teamwork
- Problem Solving
- Emotional Intelligence
- Adaptability

# Languages

Portuguese

Native

**English** 

Very good

# Fábio Ferreira

Fullstack Web Developer

# **Summary**

Fullstack Developer with over 4 years of professional experience and 6+ years of coding expertise, specializing in front-end development and UI/UX design. With a foundation in design and a career in cybersecurity, I deliver web solutions that combine aesthetics, functionality, and resilience.

For a more detailed view of my work, technologies used and other details, visit my portfolio at https://fabiof.dev

# **Technical Skills**

- Front-end Development: Typescript, React, NextJS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Storybook, MaterialUI
- Back-end Development: NodeJS, ExpressJS, PHP, MySQL, Firebase
- Other Tools: Figma, Git, GitLab, Github, Docker, Vitest, Jira, SonarQube, Windows, Linux

# **Professional Experience**

# Fullstack Developer | Security Consultant

Layer8 | Cybersecurity company

Aug 2022 - Present

- Lead developer for the company's component library, reducing development time by 50% through reusable, secure and responsive components.
- Leading the development of a cloud management platform to centralize the company's services, with features such as user and service management.
- Contributed significantly to redesigning and restructuring legacy projects to align with the new design guidelines and component library, ensuring 100% design consistency across projects.
- Consulted on security best practices for web applications, minimizing vulnerabilities and improving system reliability.

## Freelancer

Jan 2022 - Present

- Designed and developed websites focusing on responsive design and performance optimization creating a stronger online presence for clients.
- Produced diverse creative solutions, including graphic design and multimedia projects, delivering 100% client satisfaction through cohesive and polished results.



# **Personal Info**

#### Name

Fábio Miguel Alves Ferreira

## **Phone Number**

927671290

## Location

Santarém, Portugal

#### **Email**

me@fabiof.dev

## LinkedIn

https://linkedin.com/in/fabio-m-ferreira

## **GitHub**

https://github.com/fabio-m-ferreira

## **Portfolio**

https://fabiof.dev

# **Soft Skills**

- Communication
- Teamwork
- Problem Solving
- Emotional Intelligence
- Adaptability

# Languages

Portuguese Native

English Very good

# Front-End Developer | Programmer Assistant Gestix | Invoicing company

Jan 2021 - Nov 2021

- Rebuilt and redesigned the company's main website, improving performance and user experience by 20%.
- Developed a customizable, UI/UX-friendly website template for clients, Increasing customer satisfaction by 35%.
- Redesigned the back-office interface to improve usability and user experience.

# **Education**

# **Google UX Design Professional Certificate** *Corsera*

2023

Grade: average of 92.19% on all 7 courses

## **Web Development**

ETIC | Escola de Tecnologias Inovação e Criação 2019-2020

• Grade 18/20

# Multimedia Technician - High School Escola Básica e Secundária de Salvaterra de Magos

2016 - 2019

Grade: 16/20